If you think you're safe... you're DEAD wrong!
The Prowler is a horror, thriller, mystery film directed by Joseph Zito.
Thirty years after a murder on the night of Avalon Bay's graduation dance, the sleepy town's teens meet
grisly ends at the hands of a prowler once thought to be a jilted soldier home from war.
Pam MacDonald, played by Vicky Dawson.
Mark London, played by Christopher Goutman.
Maj. Chatham, played by Lawrence Tierney.
Sheriff George Fraser, played by Farley Granger.
Lisa, played by Cindy Weintraub.
Sherry, played by Lisa Dunsheath.
The Prowler is a 1981 American slasher film directed by Joseph Zito, written by Neal Barbera and Glenn Leopold, and
starring Vicky Dawson, Christopher Goutman, Lawrence Tierney, Cindy Weintraub, and Farley Granger.
The film follows a group of college students in a coastal California town who are stalked and murdered during a
graduation party by an apparent World War II veteran who killed his ex-girlfriend Rosemary Chatham in 1945.
Filmed in late 1980 in Cape May, New Jersey, The Prowler was
independently distributed by Sandhurst Releasing Corporation.
It was not a major commercial success, ranking
135th overall that year at the U.S.
box office, and grossing less than $1 million.
In some international territories, the film was released under the alternate title
Rosemary's Killer in a version that truncated many of its graphic murder sequences.
Though it has received mixed reviews from critics, The Prowler developed a cult following in the years after its release, with
praise aimed at its hard-edged violence—showcasing special effects by Tom Savini—as well as its atmosphere.
It has been named one of the greatest slasher films of all time by several publications, including
Complex and Paste magazine, and is noted as a classic of the slasher film subgenre.
The film has also been compared by a number of critics to another slasher
film of the same year with a similar plot, My Bloody Valentine.
The film explores themes of mask, murder, serial killer, slasher, maniac.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.